现在是二零二四年天津市初中学业水平考试英语学科听力测试时间。一，听力理解。
a. a, b, c 1.
在下列每小题内，你将听到一个或两个句子，并看到供选择的三幅图画。找出与你所听句子内容。相匹配的图画。
I like eating tomatoes.
2. The horse is so lovely.
3. When I go shopping, I often take a bag.
4. Ling Ling is cleaning the window.
5. She is working so hard.
Ling Ling is cleaning the window.
7. She is working so hard.
根据对话内容，从每组所给的
a, b, c 5.
三个选项中找出能回答所提问题的最佳选项。
What does your father do, 6.
is a policeman.
6. Whose camera is this?
It's Tony's. 7.
Where did you go this morning?
8. What's the matter with you, Lily?
I have a toothache.
9. Who helped the old lady near the school gate yesterday?
10. Who helped the old lady near the school gate yesterday?
根据对话内容，从每组所给的三个选项中找出能回答所提问题的最佳选项。
the school gate 10.
What sports do you like,
11. What sports do you like,
I like volleyball.
11. How much beef do you want?
How much beef do you want?
How much beef How the Great Wall,
It was very exciting.
How was your trip to the Great Wall, Betty?
13. I'd like to join the English club.
What about you, Martin?
I will join the Chinese club.
I'd like to join the English club.
What about you, Martin?
I will join the Chinese club.
14. What time is it now?
It's seven o 'clock.
Let's hurry up.
The concert will begin in ten minutes.
What time is it now?
It's seven o Let's hurry up.
The concert will begin in ten minutes.
听下面一段材料，回答第十五至第十七题。
Have you got a pet, Bill?
Yes. I've got a very clever dog.
Who gave the dog to you?
My parents gave it to me for my birthday.
Wow! How long have you had the dog?
About two years.
Do you have any pets, Amy?
Yes. I have a dog too.
We can take our dogs for a walk together.
What a great idea!
Have you got a pet,
Yes. I've got a very clever dog.
Who gave the dog to you?
My parents gave it to me for my birthday.
Wow! How long have you had the dog?
About two years.
Do you have any pets, Amy?
Yes. I have a dog too.
We can take our dogs for a walk together.
What a great idea!
Have got pet, I've clever clever dog.
听下面一段材料，回答第十八至。是第二十题。
A lot of people in Tianjin enjoy running.
Daming is one of them.
In the mornings, Daming usually runs in a park.
Then, he is ready for school.
At weekends, he sometimes runs along the Haihe River.
He really likes to see the beautiful bridges over the Haihe River.
For Daming, running is cheaper than many other sports.
He just needs some comfortable sports clothes and good running shoes.
After running, he feels relaxed.
And running also brings him a lot of fun.
A lot of people in Tianjin enjoy running.
Daming is one of them.
In the mornings, Daming usually runs in a park.
Then, he is ready for school.
At weekends, he sometimes runs along the Haihe River.
He really likes to see the beautiful bridges over the Haihe River.
For Daming, running is cheaper than many other sports.
He just needs some comfortable sports clothes and good running shoes.
After running, he feels relaxed.
And running also brings him a lot of fun.